Empresses in the Palace—the Lengend of Zhen Huan
Adopted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
[contact translators] carsenwei@yahoo.com
Theme: Unfortunate Love
Perturbed by the thoughts on my mind
no matter how hard I try to sever my love.
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For all the lovers in the world,
who can break the spell of romance?
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For all the lovers in the world,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Episode 4
Your Highness, Fuzi is dead.
Dead?
That's news to me!
When did that happen?
Her swollen dead body was just pulled out of a well.
Mind your tongue when speaking to her Highness.
It's okay.
She was running out of room crying that morning.
She must have lost her footing in the dark.
So it was my fault that she died?
Of course not. She's a maid with attitude.
A maid has to be comfortable with criticism.
Doesn't she, Mr. Jiang?
I'm not sure.
You are not sure?
You can ask anyone in my palace whether they saw Fuzi ran away.
Are you implying that we pushed her from behind?
I would't dare.
But you did!
I have offered you the chance to interrogate anyone in my palace.
I did not intend to do that.
Let me put it this way,
The Empress sent you to look into Fuzi's death.
You've asked your questions and I've answered.
You have my permission to take away my servants
for interrogation. Don't you dare question me again!
I shall take my leave.
You are all reminded that Fuzi ran out
by herself and fell into the well.
Yes, sir.
It smells so good.
My Lady, you didn't eat since you were frightened yesterday morning.
You should have breakfast today.
Not just for one day, we will be living in fear every day.
How's that?
Attendant Summer was just one of enemies to Margaret and myself.
The merciless Consort Fleur might be another.
My life is threatened by the surrounding enemies.
And My entire family will be in danger if I fall into their trap.
What should we do?
I don't know.
My Lady, would you like desserts made of the osmanthus flowers?
I can make some right away since it's in season.
You will like it.
Thank you, I will eat anything you make.
I'll ask for help.
Violet, is everything okay?
My Lady, I was just looking at the ants.
They are making a detour, seems like they are avoiding something.
That's odd. What could they be avoiding?
Xiao-Yunzi, dig up around here to see what's underneath.
Oh, there's something buried down here.
It looks like a jar.
Take it out.
What's happening?
What is it?
It's none of your business.
The jar has a strong smell.
It could be something that belonged to Lady Parfum.
Like potpourri [dried flowers and spices to put in sachets].
We might be able to use it for sachets.
Here, I got this.
Open it.
It stinks!
It's just rotten spices.
Jade, wrap it up.
You must not say anything about the jar of spices.
It would churn up gossip.
Yes.
Vermilion, let's have the desserts tomorrow.
Everyone go back to work.
Jade, let's go inside.
Take it away.
My Lady, are you all right?
I feel sick.
Can you send for Mr. Wen?
I need to see him.
Mr. Wen!
I'm glad you're on shift.
Attendant Sourire is not feeling well.
She wishes to see you.
Is she all right?
She only told me that she needed to see you.
Please go quickly.
You seem intensely scared.
I saw things I shouldn't have.
You should try to put them out of your mind.
Do you keep the promise that you made outside the temple?
Yes, I will forever put you first.
Forever is easier said than done.
My promise will stand the test of time.
I promise to repay your family for saving my father's life.
My Lady, I will do anything you say.
I don't want to sleep with the emperor.
As Shichu, I don't want that to happen either.
But as your doctor in the palace,
I hope you can do it as soon as possible.
But I'm too scared ...
Mr. Wen, I'd like to show you something.
How did this come into your possession?
The apple tree in my palace did not produce flowers this spring.
I discovered a jar by chance under the tree.
I suppose this is the cause of Lady Parfum's miscarriage
and a trace of the bitter rivalries in the palace.
Lady Parfum might not even know what caused her downfall.
It was a timely discovery. Otherwise,
all the girls in your palace would be affected.
Although I'm unable to be the man of your life,
I promise to guarantee you a peaceful life.
Can you delay my recovery?
It is basically emotional distress.
You will be fine within two weeks.
But if you wish to take it slow, I'll make it slow.
Musk can cause miscarriage or lifelong infertility.
I shall put it to good use at the dispensary.
I can't stop feeling scared.
Don't worry.
Vermilion, please walk Mr. Wen to the door.
Attendant Sourire is sick?
She caught a cold from the changing weather,
and was intensely scared lately.
She shows symptoms of a plague.
A plague?
Her health is suffering as result of emotional distress.
She has a high fever and experiences difficulty in talking.
In that case, Attendant Sourire must be quarantined.
That would be the best.
The disease is highly likely to be infectious.
I'll have Attendant Chun move out.
It might take long for Attendant Sourire to recover.
I hope you can take good care of her.
I will spare no effort.
The new concubines can serve Your Majesty tonight.
Or do you prefer to visit Consort Fleur?
You wouldn't like that, would you?
I dare not influence your decision.
The Attendance Services is ready.
Your Majesty, please select a concubine.
I do not see the name tag for Attendant Sourire.
Your Majesty, the Imperial Infirmary reported that
Attendant Sourire is in quarantine for a plague.
A plague?
It was caused by her mental illness. She was shocked when
Consort Fleur punished Attendant Summer with the Scarlet Red.
Miss Summer is paralyzed.
Why was she punished?
She intended to beat a concubine.
But that's too harsh of a penalty.
It is, but violence is the penalty for violence in the palace.
Consort Fleur's maid, Fuzi, died in a well.
And Attendant Sourire saw her dead body.
What did Consort Fleur say?
She said Fuzi lost her footing,
but Jiang Fuhai didn't believe her.
Maids are from the Eight Banners. That's ... (tut)
Keep investigating.
Well, Attendant Sourire is sick ...
But the punishment didn't affect her friends,
Lady Shen and Companion An.
[Lady Shen]
Congratulations, Lady Shen.
His Majesty selected you for tonight.
You are the first one to serve His Majesty among the new concubines.
Thank you, sir.
Lunar.
Thank you.
No need to thank me.
My Lady, you should go get ready.
But what should I do?
This is Madam Liu, she will prepare you for the service.
You will be taken to the Hall of Mental Cultivation by the Phoenix Carriage.
Good luck, My Lady.
I bid you a good night.
Take care.
Your Majesty, Lady Shen is here.
Carry her in.
Your Majesty.
It was very kind of His Majesty to send you a garden of chrysanthemums.
That's the only flower we have in autumn.
His Majesty is very fond of you, My Lady.
It's been a month since we moved in.
His Majesty favors you the most among the new concubines.
You are the most frequently summoned concubine,
with the most generous rewards.
You shouldn't talk about it in public.
The white ones are called the spring snow,
and the golden ones are the dragon cloud.
The two snuggling on one stem resembles you and His Majesty.
Stop it!
His Majesty the Emperor.
Peace to Your Majesty.
What's so funny? Let me hear it.
—Rise.
—Thank you, Your Majesty.
How do you like the flowers?
They were in full bloom in the garden,
so I had them sent to your palace.
Thank you very much. They are very nice.
Your Majesty, My Lady is deeply grateful for
the chrysanthemums. It's her favorite flower.
That's why you have them on your dress.
But why do you like chrysanthemums?
They never surrender to the cold winds.
It's a flower of integrity.
You are well read.
I didn't mean to show off.
Don't worry. Reading is good for you.
Chrysanthemum is not only known for its perseverance,
but also for its solitude from the competitive spring flowers.
I like it for its endurance of loneliness.
Thank you, I learned a lot.
I will have more chrysanthemums sent to you.
I heard that the green chrysanthemums
are in full bloom. You will have all of them.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
The name of your chamber sounds like a classroom.
I will name it Chamber of Chrysanthemums for you.
I came today to give you a task.
I want you to learn about housekeeping for the palace.
It is not an easy job.
But I know nothing about housekeeping.
That's why you should learn.
You are smart and responsible.
I have faith in you.
Managing the palace is running a household.
You will get the hang of it after a while.
Yes, I will do my best.
That's the spirit! You can do it if you put your heart into it.
The Empress is not in good health, and
Consort Fleur is not a considerate person.
I hope one day you can help me manage the harem.
My Lady, Autumn comes to see you on behalf of the Empress.
Peace to you, My Lady.
Please lie down.
Madam, what brings you here?
Her Majesty is worried about you.
Please thank Her Majesty for me.
You look gaunt and tired.
What did the doctor say?
My Lady, it's time for medicine.
Are you all right?
She is suffering physically and mentally.
She's recovering slowly taking the medicine three times a day.
There's no medicine for a mental illness.
Time is the cure.
Attendant Summer was paralyzed. She cannot walk any more.
Consort Fleur sent her to the Cold Palace because she's inconvenient.
It was her fault, but the pity of it is that you are affected.
It's all right. I can't blame her.
Of course not, but you have long been bed-ridden.
Lady Shen took advantage of that and became His Majesty's new favorite.
I'm happy for her.
But it's my guilt to make Her Majesty worried about me.
Please rest, My Lady.
I will come to see you another time.
Mr. Kang, please walk her out.
I bid you goodbye.
Attendant Sourire is a flower on the outside
but a chicken on the inside.
How could she be fine after seeing all the bloody violence?
But Companion An wasn't scared to fall ill.
She looks the most effeminate among them.
Even you submit to Consort Fleur's aggressive demeanor.
You have to bow to her even if you are a Consort with a prince.
Are you saying that I'm a coward, too?
But his Majesty is not fond of the Third Prince.
Nor does His Majesty like me for my age.
I cannot compare to Consort Fleur's youth and beauty,
or her family's prominence.
You should think about the long term.
The Third Prince is the eldest son of His Majesty.
His Majesty lost my First Prince,
and Empress Première's Second Prince.
He will value you much more than Consort Fleur for the Third Prince.
I understand, but the Third Prince isn't His Majesty's favorite son.
It is your job to make him the favorite prince.
You cannot lose heart as his mother.
But His Majesty hasn't been visiting us for months.
Your Highness, the chrysanthemums in the
Imperial Garden are not as beautiful as what we have.
Flowers are as beautiful as the owner.
Our flower puts every other palace to shame.
Watch your honeyed mouth.
Shame on my mouth, for making Her Highness frown.
Your Highness, I've never seen green chrysanthemums before!
They are special indeed.
They must be in a rush to deliver His Majesty's gifts to Your Highness.
In that case, we can take a look right here.
Come over here!
Peace to Your Highness.
Your Highness.
Are my green chrysanthemums too heavy to carry?
Just leave them there while I take a walk in the garden.
Your Highness ... the chrysanthemums ...
What's that?
They are for Lady Shen.
Of course.
Your Highness, please forgive me.
I beg your forgiveness, Your Highness.
Slap yourself.
It was all my fault!
[Chamber of Chrysanthemums]
My Lady, do you like the new plaque?
His Majesty replaced it in no time.
You hold a special place in his heart.
Do not talk in public like this.
Move faster! Take out all the chrysanthemums!
I don't want to see them again in my palace!
Here's one!
It is still early. Take your time, My Lady.
I could finally use my lower limbs.
I'm tired of sitting in a sedan chair [a status symbol].
What is wrong with you?
I am so sorry, My Lady.
It's okay, but we have to go back to get changed.
Her Majesty is expecting us.
Oh, Lady Shen remembered to come?
Your Majesty, I'm sorry for the delay.
It's okay, everyone makes a mistake sometimes.
Thank you, You Majesty.
Have a seat.
Your Majesty is very kind.
But your indulgence will spoil Lady Shen.
Indeed. From now on, can we be excused from
paying respect to Your Majesty for no reason?
Your Majesty, My Lady was late for a reason.
A eunuch spattered water on her dress,
so we went back to change it.
But she was late after all.
She has to take responsibility for it.
Your Majesty, Lady Shen has always been well-behaved.
Please forgive her this once.
You are the head of her palace.
You are accountable for her mistake as well.
Let's leave it as it is.
What would you suggest?
The law requires a thirty-time flogging for disrespect to the Empress.
The penalty can be reduced for a first offence.
Lady Shen will forfeit her stipend for the next two months.
The same penalty for Concubine Estime.
What do you think?
It was all my fault. Please spare Concubine Estime.
I agreed that a lenient penalty is enough.
It is the New Year in two months.
The forfeit will be one month instead.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
I promise this will not happen again.
You may rise.
Yes, Your Majesty.
You may leave now.
I bid Your Majesty goodbye.
I'm leaving as well.
Actually, you might have overreacted to her.
How so?
I see everyone as family.
I never took offence when you were late.
So you think I was too harsh to her.
His Majesty knows that you are lenient by nature.
That is why he selected me to assist in housekeeping.
I have to be strict to balance with your permissiveness.
As His Majesty's housekeeper, you have to
make yourself an example to the other concubines.
I hope you can take the lead in being punctual.
Of course.
But His Majesty always tells me to sleep in for a bit.
I'm afraid I have to obey his wish.
Certainly, we should always put His Majesty first.
Thank you for the clarification.
I shall leave now.
I wish to update Your Majesty on Fuzi's death.
Yes.
As suspected, she was deliberately killed.
How so?
Bruises were found on her neck and forehead.
It was reported that Consort Fleur was very displeased
when His Majesty talked to Fuzi the night before.
She's unscrupulous.
Report it truthfully to His Majesty.
I need to see the archive of the Attendance Services.
It is ready for Your Highness.
(sneer) Twice for Lady Shen,
and twice for Lady Fuca.
That is a lot.
Not at all compared to Your Highness.
His Majesty only visited the harem seven times this month.
I have to do something before it's too late.
Before they are out of my control.
His Majesty wants the Manchu concubines
to live in Harmony with us Han concubines.
Send for Lady Fuca. She has a lesson to learn.
(Lady Fuca)
As a Manchu concubine, you must learn to write Mandarin.
The first thing to do is to prepare the ink.
It's not an easy task.
This is for your own good.
It takes hours to grind ink sticks into ink.
Rebellions occurred in Qinghai Province,
threatening the stability in the Northwest.
Zhang Tingyu, what do you think?
Your Majesty, there is only one candidate I can think of.
Nian Gengyao.
Indeed.
Prince VIII and Prince IX [his brothers] are still a threat to your throne.
General Nian is the brother of Consort Fleur, and has long been in charge of the military in the western territories.
He is the best candidate in my opinion.
He made distinct contributions to my throne,
but his power has been unrestrained in the North-West.
Yue Zhongqi is a descendant of the great general Yue Fei.
He won consecutive wars in the North-West.
He is modest and sagacious.
Very well. I hereby appoint Nian Gengyao as Pacification General-in-Chief,
and Yue Zhongqi as the Counselor-in-Chief.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, Zhou Ninghai brought you pastries on behalf of Consort Fleur.
Just leave it there.
(tut) I remember receiving eastern pearls from the North-East.
You will send her the pearls in person.
It's a reward for her excellent housekeeping work.
My Lady, you should sleep early.
I'm not tired.
It's good that you can enjoy peace of mind.
Other than Lady Shen, Attendant Chun, and Companion An,
not even a wild cat would visit our palace.
The other servants have been slothful.
Even Xiao-Yinzi talked back to me.
That's not surprising. We cannot force them to work.
It sounds like someone's crying.
It must be Xiao-Yunzi. He is on the night shift.
Let's go check out.
What is wrong? Why are you crying?
Please forgive me for disturbing your night.
It's all right. Everyone has a hard time sometimes.
I wish to know what happened to you.
My brother has been seriously ill for a month.
I am very worried about him.
Don't worry, you can take a leave to look after him.
Thank you so much!
My Lady, it's cold out here. Let's go inside.
It's late. You should go sleep.
Your Majesty has been busy lately.
Here's bird's nest soup with lotus seeds.
It's an invigorating treat.
Thank you, it's palatable.
Jiang Fuhai has reported the update on Fuzi's death.
It was the result of jealousy.
I hope Your Majesty can enlighten me as to what to do.
I know she was being jealous,
but that is understandable in the harem.
She did it out of her feelings for me.
I cannot punish that. You should act as a peacemaker.
Bird's nest soup is a good treat in the winter.
You should have some as well.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
[He needs to use Consort Fleur to control her brother's power.]
Is Attendant Sourire feeling better?
Mr. Wen is taking good care of her,
but it takes time for her to recover.
Curing a disease is like reeling cocoons into silk.
A full recovery is not a fast one.
In that case, she should take it slow.
Enough with your downcast heads.
Shifu [how apprentices address their master],
Attendant Sourire is hopeless.
It's a dead-end job to work for her.
Don't even get me started.
Xiao-Youzi used to be nothing in the palace,
but now he is my equal since Lady Fuca became important.
That bastard wasn't even worthy to carry shoes for me! (spit)
It's all her fault! She's been sick for two months.
The doctor said the other day that her situation would last long.
Could it be phthisis [tuberculosis (TB)]?
Nonsense!
It will be too late to win His Majesty's affections even when she recovers. We will have to live in the very bottom of the palace.
This palace is cursed.
It was the ruin of Lady Parfum, and soon Attendant Sourire.
No, this mustn't be our tomb.
Shifu, we will follow your advice.
My advice is that we work smart.
Shifu, you are on shift today.
Huh, she's ill and inactive. Why bother to make the effort?
But it's time that we consider working for someone else.
My Lady wanted to have some tea. Why is it taking so long?
I have to to boil water before making tea.
I'm afraid she has to wait.
Besides, the Household Department did not allot tea to her for this month. She will only have hot water later.
I saw you having tea yesterday.
How could there not be any tea for My Lady?
Did you take her tea for yourself?
You have to provide evidence when you say something like that.
You are not living at home any more.
Violet, is that how you should speak to My Lady's dowry maid?
You should make tea quickly when My Lady requests.
Go get tea from the Household Department later.
Attendant Sourire is not likely to recover.
Shifu, please let me follow you to work for Concubine Beauté.
Mr. Kang, you should inform My Lady if you are leaving,
so we can congratulate you on your new job.
I will tell her soon or later. Let's go see her now.
My Lady.
My Lady, I'm afraid I cannot serve you any more.
What's wrong? Calm yourself down.
Theme: The Lonely Phoenix
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
[contact translators] carsenwei@yahoo.com
I dimly recall the colorful blooms in every summer.
They are as distant as the autumn moon in the water.
He loved me with a volatile heart.
And before I knew it, we fell apart.
Behind me are the promises and longing.
Before me lie the flute and the zither.
I loved you with my body and soul
But you hurt me from head to toe.
My wish ran athwart
and I ended up a fool of my destiny.
My love was the wind-swept flowers from a tree.
A plum bloomed in winter hoping for a fruitful summer.
But the irresistible winds of destiny destroyed her wish.
You can hear the flapping of a phoenix
but you will never see it.
What you see is the falling leaves from the phoenix tree.
The falling leaves from the phoenix tree.